# 大家好 今天去看一下兄弟家的羊
Hi everyone! Today we're gonna have a look at our buddy's goats.
# 聽說生了很多小羊哦
I've heard that a lot of baby goats were born.
# 你看 他家的羊就在那裡 你看
Look! His goats are just over there, look!
# 很山的 這裡喲
It's very hilly, this place.
# 看一下
Let's take a look.
# 你看 這個
Look! These are,
# 香藤子 那麼多今年 一樹都是哦 你看
"xiang tengzi" (untranslatable local wild fruits). There are so many this year, all over the tree. Look!
# 這裡都十幾二十串啦
Here are already ten to twenty bunches.
# 裡面還有很多的
And there are a lot more inside.
# 太多啦 真的
Really, too many
# 到秋天的時候我們就過來摘
We can come and pick them in autumn.
# 帶了兩條鏈子
I have two chains with me.
# 你來抓我來拴
You catch it and I chain it.
# 嘿 走
Hey! Let's go!
# 走 帶你回家
Let's go! I'll take you home.
# 帶你回家 走啦
We're going home! C'mon!
# 我們回去吃好吃的
We have very good food at home.
# 走啦 走啦 聽話 聽話 聽話 帶你回家 走走走
C'mon, c'mon! Good goat, be a good goat. We're going home. Go, go, go!
# 剛剛羊都跑了一隻
One of the goats has just run away.
# 唉 鬱悶死啦
Ay! Damn it!
# 追了 追了一大片山都沒抓到它
I've run, run after it all over the hill, without any success.
# 這是甚麼
What is it?
# 我不知道是甚麼
I have no ideas what it is.
# 好多 這藤子上長出來的哦
A lot! They're growing from the vines, you know.
# 像不像巴豆
Does it look like croton?
# 專治拉稀的這個 (註︰巴豆不是瀉藥嗎？管他)
I means, the one which cures diarrhea.
# 從來沒見過那麼大的豆子
I've never seen any beans of this size.
# 那麼大的
They're so big!
# 你看 它跟手掌一半那麼大
Look! It's half as big as my palm.
# 好多 好多毛毛哇
It's rather, rather furry.
# 熟的時候我掰開來看一下 看是甚麼種子
When they become ripe, I'm gonna open it and see what kind of seeds they are.
# 拿幾個回去種 那麼大
How about planting some at my place? It's so big.
# 像豆子一樣
They're like beans.
# 啊 回家啦 回家啦 沒精神 (註︰這個沒精神應該是指沒心情加上累，沒有很好的翻譯，所以改了一下)
Ah! Let's go home, go home. It's a bad day.
# 還有那隻羊回去拴起來 別那隻都跑啦
I'm gonna tether up the remaining goat. Don't let it run away.
# 你看 就剩一條羊啦 還有一條都跑啦
Look! Only one goat remains. The other one has run away.
# 哎呀 明天我再過來 看一下它有沒有回家
Aya! I'll come here again tomorrow and see, if it has gone back home.
# 明天再來摘 抓 把它抓回去
Let me come and pick, catch, catch it back tomorrow.
# 把它拉回來啦 它有點怕那個小狗
So we've taken it back. It's a bit scared of the doggy.
# 剛才小狗嚇了它 嚇了它一下
The doggy has just scared, scared it.
# 啊 現在
Ah! Now,
# 給了 搞點那像草給它
I've given, fetched it some elephant grass.
# 它很喜歡吃 但是一直看著那個小狗
It likes the elephant grass. But it keeps staring at the doggy.
# 沒事的 不會咬你的
No worries. It's not gonna bite you.
# 它咬了你 我就打它
I'll beat it if it bites you.
# 這羊可能 可能懷孕啦
The goat is, perhaps it's pregnant.
# 肚子那麼大
It has such a big belly.
# 買一送一
Buy one get one free
# 來 給它象草葉子給它吃
C'mon! I'm giving it some elephant grass leaves.
# 香不香
Smells good?
# 這個象草 很好吃的
The elephant grass, is really tasty!
# 你不吃等餓扁你去 你就會吃
You're not eating. But you'll eat when you starts starving.
# 多吃點啊
C'mon, eat more,
# 長大一點
And be a big goat!
# 那麼瘦
You're so skinny.
# 沒肉 全是骨頭
You have just bones, and hardly any flesh.
# 肯定剛來到這個陌生的環璄 (註︰英文沒有很適合的字來表達「陌生」這個概念，所以稍稍改了字眼)
I'm sure that everything here seems very unfamiliar to it.
# 太陌生啦
It's a completely new environment.
# 一下子接受不了
It takes time for it to get used to this place.
# 你看
Look!
# 它怕那個小狗
It's scared of the doggy.